<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<module name="Ft.Xml.Xslt.XsltFunctions">
  <modification-date>2005-08-30 18:52:10</modification-date>
  <abstract>Standard XSLT functions</abstract>
  <description>Copyright 2005 Fourthought, Inc. (USA).
Detailed license and copyright information: http://4suite.org/COPYRIGHT
Project home, documentation, distributions: http://4suite.org/</description>
  <version>0.0</version>
  <functions>
    <function public="yes" name="Current" id="Current">
      <abstract>Implementation of current().</abstract>
      <description>Returns a node-set that has the current node as its only member.</description>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
    <function public="yes" name="Document" id="Document">
      <abstract>Implementation of document().</abstract>
      <description>The XSLT 1.0 document function returns the root node of a single
XML document or of the union of multiple XML documents. The
arguments are reduced to a set of URIs that indicate the documents
to parse.

The first argument is required and provides a set of URI
references, each of which may be absolute or relative. If it
is a node-set, then the URI references are the string-values of
each node in the set. If the argument is any other kind of
object, the URI reference is the string-value of object.

The second argument is optional. If given, it provides a base URI
for normalizing relative URI references, it must be a node-set,
and only its first node (in document order) is used. The base URI
for all relative references is the URI of the entity from which
the node originated. If the node-set is empty, an exception is
raised (see XSLT 1.0 erratum E14).

If the second argument is not given, then the base URI depends on
whether the first argument is a node-set. If the first argument is
a node-set, then the base URI for each node in the set is the
entity from which that node originated. Otherwise, the base URI is
the URI of the entity containing the node with the document() call
(this URI is usually that of the stylesheet itself, but could be
an imported stylesheet or even a parsed general entity).

Thus,

document('') typically refers to the stylesheet itself, prior to
whitespace stripping;

document('http://somehost/foo.xml') refers to the document at
that absolute URI;

document('foo.xml') typically refers to the foo.xml document
relative to the stylesheet;

document('http://somehost/foo.xml', $ns) where $ns is a non-empty
node-set refers to the document at that absolute URI ($ns is
ignored);

document('foo.xml', $ns) where $ns is a non-empty node-set refers
to the foo.xml document relative to the URI of the entity from
which $ns[1] originated;

document($ns) where $ns is a non-empty node-set is treated as if
it were
document(string($ns[1]),$ns[1])|document(string($ns[2]),$ns[2])
and so on; and

document($ns, $ns2) where $ns is a node-set and $ns2 is a
non-empty node-set is treated as if it were
document(string($ns[1]),$ns2[1])|document(string($ns[2]),$ns2[1])
and so on.</description>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
        <arg name="object"/>
        <arg default="None" name="nodeSet"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
    <function public="yes" name="ElementAvailable" id="ElementAvailable">
      <abstract>Implementation of element-available().</abstract>
      <description>Returns true if and only if the expanded-name represented by the
given QName is the name of an instruction. If the expanded-name has
a namespace URI equal to the XSLT namespace URI, then it refers to
an element defined by XSLT. Otherwise, it refers to an extension
element. If the expanded-name has a null namespace URI, the
element-available function will return false.</description>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
        <arg name="qname"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
    <function public="yes" name="FormatNumber" id="FormatNumber">
      <abstract>Implementation of format-number().</abstract>
      <description>Converts its first argument to a string using the format pattern
string specified by the second argument and the decimal-format
named by the third argument (see the xsl:decimal-format element),
or the default decimal-format, if there is no third argument.

The format pattern string is in the syntax specified by the JDK 1.1
DecimalFormat class. The decimal-format name must be a QName. It is
an error if the stylesheet does not contain a declaration of the
decimal-format with the specified expanded-name.</description>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
        <arg name="number"/>
        <arg name="formatString"/>
        <arg default="None" name="decimalFormatName"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
    <function public="yes" name="FunctionAvailable" id="FunctionAvailable">
      <abstract>Implementation of function-available().</abstract>
      <description>Returns true if and only if the expanded-name represented by the
given QName is the name of a function in the function library.
If the expanded-name has a non-null namespace URI, then it refers
to an extension function; otherwise, it refers to a function
defined by XPath or XSLT.</description>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
        <arg name="qname"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
    <function public="yes" name="GenerateId" id="GenerateId">
      <abstract>Implementation of generate-id().</abstract>
      <description>Returns a string that uniquely identifies the node in the argument
node-set that is first in document order. If the argument node-set
is empty, the empty string is returned. If the argument is omitted,
it defaults to the context node.</description>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
        <arg default="None" name="nodeSet"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
    <function public="yes" name="Key" id="Key">
      <abstract>Implementation of key().</abstract>
      <description>The first argument specifies the name of the key. When the second
argument to the key function is of type node-set, then the result
is the union of the result of applying the key function to the
string value of each of the nodes in the argument node-set.
When the second argument to key is of any other type, the argument
is converted to a string as if by a call to the string function; it
returns a node-set containing the nodes in the same document as the
context node that have a value for the named key equal to this string.</description>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
        <arg name="qname"/>
        <arg name="keyList"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
    <function public="yes" name="SystemProperty" id="SystemProperty">
      <abstract/>
      <description/>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
        <arg name="qname"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
    <function public="yes" name="UnparsedEntityUri" id="UnparsedEntityUri">
      <abstract>Implementation of unparsed-entity-uri().</abstract>
      <description>Returns the URI of the unparsed entity with the specified name in
the same document as the context node. It returns the empty string
if there is no such entity.</description>
      <arguments>
        <arg name="context"/>
        <arg name="name"/>
      </arguments>
    </function>
  </functions>
  <globals>
    <global public="yes" name="CoreFunctions" id="CoreFunctions">
      <value>{(None, 'current'): &lt;function Current&gt;, (None, 'document'): &lt;function Document&gt;, (None, 'element-available'): &lt;function ElementAvailable&gt;, (None, 'format-number'): &lt;function FormatNumber&gt;, (None, 'function-available'): &lt;function FunctionAvailable&gt;, (None, 'generate-id'): &lt;function GenerateId&gt;, (None, 'key'): &lt;function Key&gt;, (None, 'system-property'): &lt;function SystemProperty&gt;, (None, 'unparsed-entity-uri'): &lt;function UnparsedEntityUri&gt;}</value>
    </global>
    <global public="yes" name="EMPTY_NAMESPACE" id="EMPTY_NAMESPACE">
      <value>None</value>
    </global>
    <global public="yes" name="FT_EXT_NAMESPACE" id="FT_EXT_NAMESPACE">
      <value>'http://xmlns.4suite.org/ext'</value>
    </global>
    <global public="yes" name="XSL_NAMESPACE" id="XSL_NAMESPACE">
      <value>u'http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform'</value>
    </global>
    <global public="no" name="__version__" id="__version__">
      <value>'0.0'</value>
    </global>
  </globals>
</module>
